<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[gravenuance]]></title><description><![CDATA[a blog focusing on issues surrounding technology, culture, and art]]></description><link>https://gravenuance.com</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 13:34:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[how to pirate books and academic articles, and bypass paywalls]]></title><description><![CDATA[disclaimer: this article exists for educational purposes and because I believe in the open sharing of knowledge and information 💕 if any of…]]></description><link>https://gravenuance.com/how-to-pirate-books-and-articles-and-bypass-paywalls/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://gravenuance.com/how-to-pirate-books-and-articles-and-bypass-paywalls/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;disclaimer: this article exists for educational purposes and because I believe in the open sharing of knowledge and information&lt;/em&gt; 💕&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if any of the websites mentioned in the article are inaccessible for any reason, download and enable &lt;a href=&quot;https://1.1.1.1/&quot;&gt;1.1.1.1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;how to find a book&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;note: this method works for most books. If your book is too niche, you have to work some internet magic to find it (private trackers and so on)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://unblocked-pw.github.io/&quot;&gt;unblocked-pw.github.io&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;scroll all the way down to and click LibGen, select ISBN in “Search in fields”, type in the ISBN of the book you want and press search&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;if your search turns out empty, reset “Search in fields” and try searching by title and author (and if that turns out empty, you might be out of luck).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the format you’d like to download is up to you. i prioritize EPUB and PDF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EPUB is the most widely supported vendor-independent XML-based e-book format according to Wikipedia. if you have a Kindle, you have to download MOBI instead of EPUB (don’t get a Kindle; just my 2 cents)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;click the title of the book&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;find the br❌ken image on left side of the new page and click it&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;then, click any of the mirrors listed (Cloudflare, IPFS.io, Infura) and save the book&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;congrats, you’ve solved a modern day internet puzzle ✨&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;how to find an academic article&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://unblocked-pw.github.io/&quot;&gt;unblocked-pw.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;scroll all the way down to and click SciHub, enter the article’s DOI and press search&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;how to bypass paywalls&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/&quot;&gt;installing firefox and using it as your primary browser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;head over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/bypass-paywalls-firefox/&quot;&gt;the extensions webpage and install the ‘bypass paywalls’ extension&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the source code is available &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iamadamdev/bypass-paywalls-chrome&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for those interested&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p.s. i don’t listen to audiobooks much, but if you’re looking for audiobooks, go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://unblocked-pw.github.io/&quot;&gt;unblocked-pw.github.io&lt;/a&gt;, scroll down to and click AudiobookBay 🧚‍♀️&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>